- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- ♪ Ohh...
- ♪ 哦...
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
♪
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[laid-back steel guitar]
[悠闲的钢吉他]
♪
[elegant harpsichord music]
[优雅的羽管键琴音乐]
- Well, what do you think?
- 嗯，你觉得怎么样？
Do you love it?
你喜欢它吗？
- Mr. Tentacles, I simply
cannot express
- 触手先生，我只是
无法表达
my true feelings about
your work!
我的真实感受
你的工作！
- Yes, I realize my artistic
brilliance can be overwhelming.
- 是的，我意识到我的艺术
光辉可以是压倒性的。
- Quite frankly...
- 坦白说...
[inhales]
[吸气]
It stinks!
太臭了！
- Yes, and--what?!
- 是的，还有——什么？！
Now, see here!
现在，看这里！
Maybe this museum is too
low-brow
也许这个博物馆也是
低俗的
for this masterpiece!
为了这部杰作！
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
How dare you! Be gone!
你怎么敢！走吧！
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
- And take your putrid painting
with you!
- 拿走你腐烂的画
和你在一起！
It has no place in this
museum's art collection!
在此没有它的位置
博物馆的艺术收藏品！
- Won't anyone save my
precious painting!?
- 没有人能救我吗
珍贵的画！？
- Got it!
- 知道了！
- Why couldn't it have been
anyone else?
- 为什么不可能
还有其他人吗？
Give me that! [straining]
给我那个！ [紧张]
What are you doing here?!
你在这里做什么？
- Patrick is the museum's
new security guard!
- 帕特里克是博物馆的
新保安！
And he's giving me
a guided tour.
他给我
导游陪同游览。
- [grunts] Heh.
- [咕哝] 呵呵。
- Him? Security?!
- 他？安全？！
Pfft! Ha!
噗！哈!
This museum's dumber
than I thought.
这个博物馆更蠢
比我想象的要多。
Hold on, Squidward...
等等，章鱼哥……
if that pointy-headed
pea brain
如果那个尖头的
豌豆脑
is the security guard
for this place,
是保安
对于这个地方，
then I could sneak my artwork
into the museum!
然后我就可以偷偷偷看我的作品
进博物馆！
- Sneak what into a where?
- 将什么东西潜入何处？
- Think louder, Squidward!
You're mumbling!
- 大声思考，章鱼哥！
你在嘀咕！
- Get out of my head!
- 从我脑子里滚出去！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- [squeaking]
- [吱吱声]
- [sighs] Give me that!
- [叹气]给我那个！
both: Bye!
两人：再见！
- Bon voyage!
- 一路顺风！
- Keep making pretty pictures!
- 继续制作漂亮的图片！
The first exhibit on our
tour is...
我们的第一个展览
旅游是...
[eerie music]
[诡异的音乐]
- Whoa!
- 哇！
- The employee locker room!
- 员工更衣室！
- Wow!
- 哇！
Your life is so
glamorous!
你的生活就是这样
迷人！
- You could be my
junior assistant!
- 你可以是我的
初级助理！
- Really?!
- Sure.
- 真的吗？！
- 当然。
There's a ton of uniforms
in these metal boxes!
有很多制服
在这些金属盒子里！
Check it out!
一探究竟！
Let me just get my key.
让我去拿我的钥匙。
[straining]
[紧张]
Put this on!
- Okay!
穿上这个！
- 好的！
[yells]
[喊叫]
Well, how do I look?
嗯，我看起来怎么样？
- Guard-tastic!
- 防守太棒了！
[indistinct chatter]
[模糊的喋喋不休]
Now, rule number one
of guarding is,
现在，第一条规则
的守护是，
don't let visitors touch stuff.
不要让访客触摸东西。
- No touchy, no feely.
Eye-eye.
- 没有敏感，没有感觉。
眼对眼。
- Rule number B: no running!
- 规则 B：禁止跑步！
[children shouting]
[孩子们喊叫]
- Single file, children,
single file.
- 单列，儿童，
单个文件。
- But stampeding is just fine.
- 但是踩踏就可以了。
And the most important rule
of all is,
还有最重要的规则
最重要的是，
don't let visitors steal stuff!
不要让游客偷东西！
If you see anybody suspicious,
如果你看到有人可疑
you give them the ol'
stink eye!
你给他们 ol'
臭眼睛！
Hmm.
唔。
- [chuckling]
- [轻笑]
Hm?
嗯？
[eyes hissing]
[眼睛发出嘶嘶声]
[groaning]
[呻吟]
- Now you try!
- 现在你试试吧！
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- Whew.
- 呼。
[screams]
[尖叫声]
- [straining]
- [紧张]
[squeaking]
[吱吱声]
- Mmmm.
- 嗯。
Ooh, delicious. [giggling]
哦，好吃。 [咯咯笑]
- Ohh...
- 哦...
- You'll get there, pal.
- 你会到达那里的，朋友。
Behold, SpongeBob.
看哪，海绵宝宝。
Before laughter, there was
the pre-hysterical period.
在笑声之前，有
歇斯底里前期。
- [gasps] Oh, look, honey!
- [喘气]哦，看，亲爱的！
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
- What an excellent example
- 多么好的例子啊
of the primitive security
guard era.
原始安全的
后卫时代。
- Ooh! I almost forgot
rule number fourth!
- 哦！我差点忘了
第四条规则！
No flash photography!
禁止闪光摄影！
[both scream]
[两人尖叫]
And that is everything I know
about being a security guard.
这就是我所知道的一切
关于当一名保安。
[chomping]
[咀嚼]
[belches]
- Oh!
[打嗝]
- 哦！
- Now, I'll teach you
everything I don't know.
- 现在我来教你
一切我都不知道。
[crickets chirping]
[蟋蟀鸣叫]
Right this way.
就这样。
- Oh, boy!
- 哦，孩子！
An extinct wooly mollusk!
一种已灭绝的毛状软体动物！
[trumpeting]
[喇叭声]
Aw, this little guy looks like
my Gary.
噢，这个小家伙看起来像
我的加里。
Meow.
喵。
Too bad we aren't
allowed to touch anything.
可惜我们不是
允许触摸任何东西。
- Pfft! SpongeBob,
- 噗！海绵宝宝，
the rules don't
apply to us.
规则没有
向我们申请。
We're security!
- Hooray!
我们是保安！
- 万岁！
[giggling]
[咯咯笑]
Pffft!
噗！
[giggling]
[咯咯笑]
[buzzing]
[嗡嗡声]
- Is that it?
Come on.
- 是这样吗？
快点。
Do something!
做点什么吧！
[growling]
[咆哮]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
Why! Won't! You! Work?!
为什么！惯于！你！工作？！
Huh?
啊？
[both scream]
[两人尖叫]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
And here we see the ancient
junk of the great empire
在这里我们看到了古老的
伟大帝国的垃圾
of Pat-Lantis!
帕特·兰蒂斯！
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
- [whistles]
- [口哨]
- Hm?
- 嗯？
Hey! No touching
the exhibits, buddy!
嘿！禁止触摸
展品，伙计！
[grunting] Oof!
[咕噜声]噢！
[rumbling]
[隆隆声]
[all scream]
[所有人尖叫]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
[toilet flushes]
[厕所冲水]
- Hmm...
- 唔...
[gasps]
[喘气]
- Sorry about that, mister.
- 抱歉，先生。
Ooh!
哦！
- Huh? Oh, look, Patrick!
A mummy!
- 啊？哦，看，帕特里克！
一个木乃伊！
- Mummy! Awww.
- 妈妈！噢。
- Uh, no, Patrick.
It's not your mother--
- 呃，不，帕特里克。
这不是你妈妈——
- Love your new look!
How's dad?
- 喜欢你的新造型！
爸爸怎么样？
- Never mind.
- 没关系。
[stampeding]
[踩踏]
Will those kids be okay
in there?
那些孩子们会好吗
在那里？
- Oh sure, Mummy loves kids!
- 哦，当然，妈妈喜欢孩子！
I think this is yours.
我想这是你的。
- Hm. Huh?
- 嗯。啊？
[stampeding]
[踩踏]
Single file, children.
孩子们，单列。
[groans]
[呻吟]
- Ooooh.
- 噢。
Ooooh!
哦哦！
Ooh-ooh-ooh.
哦哦哦。
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
- Hee!
both: Whatcha doin'?!
- 嘿！
两人：在做什么？！
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
I'm cleaning centuries of dirt
from this priceless painting.
我正在清理几个世纪的污垢
来自这幅无价的画作。
- Going too slow!
- 速度太慢了！
- I think I know how we can
speed things along!
- 我想我知道我们该怎么做
加快进度！
- Please stand back
for your safety.
- 请往后站
为了您的安全。
Ooh!
哦！
[grinding]
[研磨]
[bells jangling]
[铃声叮当作响]
Here you go!
干得好！
[shattering]
[破碎]
[sunny music]
[阳光音乐]
♪
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[maniacal laughter]
[疯狂的笑声]
- Now to hang my masterpiece.
- 现在要挂我的杰作了。
Mm-hmm...
嗯嗯...
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[chuckling]
[轻笑]
[muttering]
[嘀咕]
- Ooh! I didn't know they had
pin the tail on the sea-donkey!
- 哦！我不知道他们有
把尾巴钉在海驴身上！
- This place has everything!
- 这个地方什么都有！
[both giggling]
[两人都咯咯笑]
[camera shutter clicks]
[相机快门声]
- Hey! No flash photography!
- 嘿！禁止闪光摄影！
- Whew!
- 哇！
[chuckling]
[轻笑]
[gasps]
[喘气]
- Yahhh!
- 啊哈！
- [neighing]
- [嘶嘶声]
- The winner!
- 获胜者！
- [chuckling]
- [轻笑]
- Did you see that guy?
- Yeah!
- 你看到那个人了吗？
- 是的！
No running allowed!
Let's get him!
不允许跑步！
我们来抓住他吧！
- Hee-haw!
- 嘻哈！
Ah! They're finally gone!
啊!他们终于走了！
[chortling]
[咯咯笑]
Hmm? Hmm.
唔？唔。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
- Hey, Patrick?
I think that guy's trying to--
- 嘿，帕特里克？
我认为那家伙正试图——
- Touch that painting!
- 触摸那幅画！
- Hmm? Hmm.
- 唔？唔。
[chuckling]
[轻笑]
- Uh-oh!
- And now he's stealing it!
- 呃哦！
- 现在他正在偷东西！
- [imitates siren]
- [模仿塞壬]
- [panting]
- [气喘吁吁]
Oh, no. Dead end!
哦，不。死胡同！
[sitar music]
[西塔琴音乐]
[gasps]
[喘气]
- Stop, thief!
- 住手，小偷！
- [panting]
- [气喘吁吁]
Ha, ha--oh!
哈、哈——哦！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
- Looks like this case
is all wrapped up.
- 看起来像这个案例
都被包裹起来了。
- [mumbling]
- [咕哝]
- Thank you, Mummy.
- Anytime, sweetie.
- 谢谢你，妈妈。
- 任何时候，亲爱的。
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
[all panting]
[全都气喘吁吁]
- [wheezing]
We're never gonna catch him!
- [喘息]
我们永远抓不到他！
- Ooh! The woolly mollusk!
- 哦！毛茸茸的软体动物！
Ah!
啊!
- Hi-ya!
- 嗨呀！
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
- [roars]
- [咆哮]
- Hmm.
- Um...
- 唔。
- 嗯...
[grunting] Come on.
[咕哝]来吧。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- [panting]
Ha, ha! Too slow!
- [气喘吁吁]
哈，哈！太慢了！
[stampeding]
[踩踏]
- Single file, children.
- 单列，孩子们。
Single file.
单个文件。
- [chuckling]
- [轻笑]
[both shout]
[两人大喊]
- We've secured
the purple-tater, over.
- 我们已经确保了
紫色土豆，结束了。
[siren wailing]
[警笛哀号]
- [sighs]
- [叹气]
Hmm?
唔？
- There! Back where you belong.
- 那里！回到属于你的地方。
- [mumbling] It's beautiful!
- [咕哝] 太漂亮了！
- You actually like
that eyesore?
- 你其实喜欢
那个碍眼的？
- Why, it's the greatest
painting I've ever seen...
- 为什么，这是最伟大的
我见过的画...
hanging in a museum!
挂在博物馆里！
[cackling]
[咯咯笑]
- Okay, that's enough, weirdo.
- 好吧，够了，怪人。
- [chuckling]
- [轻笑]